Forward-thinking software developer with 16 years of experience in web application development, mobile app development, and business intelligence development. Successfully operates in agile-like development environments, taking ownership of projects from start to finish, delivering value, and employing proactive problem solving and resolution. Brings significant expertise in web development stack, single-page applications, and mobile app development.

Highlighted Achievements

- ✓ Created Amazon Alexa skill and Google Assistant appto provide a subset of features from Atlatl's second largest revenue generating software product
- ✓ Served as core developer on user-interface redesign project, which converted multi-page web application comprised of JSF, Ajax, and Ext-JS frameworks into a GWT/GXT single-page app
- ✓ Architected and developed Atlatl's first native iOS universal app published in the Apple app store to provide mobile access to company's fillable forms subscriber base
- ✓ Developed dynamic reporting solution for webbased software product by working on web development stack to provide a customizable report framework and eliminate overhead of persistent development and custom ad-hoc report maintenance
- ✓ Built and integrated client-facing data import and export functionality into fillable forms hosted software service, allowing data portability for core system objects and providing users fast start-up time
- ✓ Developed automated Android app build process for mobile app CMS using Android SDK Tools and Java to create signed APK file for distribution to app marketplace
- ✓ Developed ETL solution using SQL Server DTS and Transact-SQL stored procedures to provide data used in daily and quarterly reporting against transactional management system

Technical Expertise

Languages: Java, Objective-C, SQL, PL/SQL, C++, C, JavaScript

Frameworks/APIs: Java EE, Hibernate, Primefaces, Cocoa Touch, iOS SDK, Android SDK, JAX-RS, RESTEasy, JSP, JSF, Apache POI, iText, Thymeleaf, Mailgun, Sencha Touch, Quartz Scheduler, JavaMail, Bootstrap

Web Application Client Side Frameworks: GWT, GXT, AngularJS

Tools: Eclipse, MyEclipse, Xcode, TortoiseSVN, SVN, SourceSafe, Git, Bugzilla, Jenkins, Hudson, Grunt, Balsamiq Mockups, phpMyFAQ

Databases: Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL **Protocols/Standards**: REST, JSON, XML

Other: JBoss Application Server, Apache Web Server, Bitnami, Business Objects

Work Experience

TRIANGLE SITE DESIGN, Raleigh, NC

Civil Designer & IT Administrator, 02-2019 to Present

- Involved in land development design, construction document preparation, site inspection of construction work and field surveying
- Utilize AutoCAD to draft, scale and fine-tune drawings and maps for land development projects, and create concept plans and erosion and sediment control plans
- Responsible for daily management, upkeep and configuration of technology infrastructure. Designed and implemented significant changes, resulting in increased office productivity and improved cyber security

ATLATL, Durham, NC

Software Developer, 08-2008 to 02-2019

- Worked closely with a small team of developers and customer support to build, enhance, and maintain in-house web and mobile applications used by small businesses
- Executed data modeling, business logic, and user-interface projects
- Managed all aspects of data layer needs, including database schema design, data migrations, ORM infrastructure needs implementation, and data retrieval and modification queries
- Modified existing software by engaging with customer support to identify and correct problems and improve product performance
- Developed and maintained iOS and Android apps that provided mobile access for the subscription base of hosted software
- Built and utilized REST and RPC SOA solutions in web and mobile application development

DUNN SOLUTIONS, Raleigh, NC

Business Intelligence Developer/Consultant, 03-2004 to 08-2008

- Worked closely with clients from mid-sized to large corporations to create business intelligence solutions to meet business analytics needs
- Designed and implemented database schemas tuned for high-volume report querying
- Implemented extract, transform, and load processes using ETL tools and database stored procedures for populating datamarts
- Developed and maintained semantic layer data representations and created and tested complex data reports using BusinessObjects

On the Side

CHEAPTHYCABLE.COM, 08-2016 to 10-2017

Developed crowdsourcing web application that allowed participants to see what others were paying for cable and internet in their area with the goal of providing leveraging power in negotiating a lower bill. Developed using J2EE web container, Hibernate, Angular JS, Bootstrap, and other popular APIs such as Thymeleaf, Mailgun and Disqus.

Education

NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY, Raleigh, NC Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, 2003